명왕성은 행성이 아니라고
I'm telling you Pluto
ain't a planet.
언제부터?
Since when?
IAU가 그렇다고 했을 때부터
Since the IAU said so.
누구?
The who?
규칙 만드는 책상물림하는 사람들이 모인 곳이야
A bunch of pencil necks
who make the rules.
나는 그런 규칙에 구애되지 않을 거야
They don't make
the rules for me.
계속 "행성"이라고 부를 거라고
I'm going with 쐏lanet.
책상물림하니 말인데, 누가 너를 열심히 보고 있네
Speaking of pencil necks,
somebody's got
an eyeball on you.
저 사람은 IAU가 뭔지 아는가 알아봐
See if he knows
what the IAU is.
재미 좀 보고 싶으세요?
Looking for some fun?
그거 좋지
That works.
늦었잖아요!
You're late!
더 이상 하기 전에 저를
보호해주실 수 있는지 알아야겠어요
But before we go anywhere,
I need to know
you can protect me.
제 가족도요
And my family.
당신은 이제 안전해요
You're safe now.
당신 가족도 보호할 겁니다
I'll make sure your
family is, too.
이 사람들을 몰라서 하는 소리예요!
You don't know these people!
어디까지 할 수 있는지 몰라서 하는 소리라고요
You don't know
what they can do!
오, 알고 말고요
Oh, yeah, we do.
그래서 제가 온 겁니다
That's why I'm here.
저를 믿으세요. 이제 안전합니다
Trust me.
You're safe.
♪ NCIS 12x19 ♪
Patience
솵 NCIS 12x19 솵
Original Air Date on March 31, 2015
마크 하몬
(제쓰로 깁스 역)
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
마이크 웨덜리
(안토니 "토니" 디노조 역)
폴리 페렛
(애비 슈토 역)
솵 솵
션 머레이
(티모시 맥기 역)
브라이언 디에첸
(팔머 역)
에밀리 위커샴
(비숍 역)
로키 캐롤
(리온 밴스 역)
데이비드 맥칼럼
(도널드 "더키" 맬러드 역)
Great. Thank you.
보스, 여자들이 말하기를 총격을 가한
사람은 검은색 SUV에 타고 있었다네요
Well, boss, girls say
that, uh, the shooter
was someone in a black SUV.
- 운전자가 누군지는 봤대?
- 봤다고 해도 말하지 않으려 해요
They get a look
at the driver?
If they did,
they're not saying.
겁먹은 것 같아요
I think they're scared.
여기 있어요. 잔돈은 가지세요
Here you go.
Keep the change.
누군가 본 사람이 있을 거야, 맥기
디노조 데리고 주변을 탐색해봐
Somebody saw something, McGee.
Take DiNozzo,
canvass the area.
음, 보스. 디노조는 오늘 출근
안 했다는 거 기억하세요?
Uh, boss, DiNozzo isn't
here today, remember?
이게 벗어났다고 생각하는 순간 다시 불려왔지
Just when I thought I was out,
they pull me back in.
우-야!
Ooh-yah!
- 친구들이랑 애틀랜틱 시티로 간 줄 알았는데요
- 뭐, 비행기는 2시에 뜨니까
Thought you were in
Atlantic City with your buddies.
Well, my flight doesn't
leave until 2:00.
보스가 그 전까지는 좀 도와달라고 해서
Gibbs asked me to
help out till then.
너 혼자서 감당할 수 없다고 생각하는 모양이야
내 재킷 가지고 올게
Clearly, he didn't think you
could handle it by yourself.
Let me get my jacket.
오, 마치 보스가 그렇게 말한 것처럼 표현하네요
Oh, please.
Like he actually said that.
잠깐, 정말 보스가 그렇게 말했어요? / 고맙네
Wait, did he actually say that?
Oh, thank you.
매출이 인류의 가장 오래된 직업일 뿐 아니라
동물도 매춘을 한다는 증거가 있다네
Not only is prostitution
humanity's oldest profession,
there is also evidence that
animals engage in it, too.
예를 들어, 남극 펭귄은...
For example, the
Antarctic penguin...
스틸레토 힐은 얼음에서는 쥐약이겠네요
Stilettos must be
murder on the ice.
(laughs)
농담이었어요 / 아니지, 농담을 던지려고 시도한 거지
That was a joke.
No, that was an
attempt at a joke.
좋은 아침이네, 엘레노어!
오늘 영광의 주인공은 누구인가?
Good morning, Eleanor!
Uh, to whom do we have
the pleasure?
안녕하세요, 더키 박사님
Good morning, Ducky.
Well...
현재 아는 건 여자 피해자 이름이 롤리타이고
all we have
is Lolita
for the female victim.
남자 피해자는 병장 대니얼 하비라는 거예요
And the male is
Petty Officer 2nd Class
Daniel Harvey.
상관에게 통보하도록 해 / 알겠습니다
Notify his commanding officer.
On it.
총격은 여성에게 집중된 것으로 보이네
The gunfire appears
to have been
concentrated on the female.
맥기 요원과 이야기를 끝낼 즈음에는
정확한 결과를 말해줄 수 있을 걸세
But I'll have an accurate idea
when you're done
with Agent McGee.
뭐라고? / 맥기 요원이 뒤에 서 있어요
Huh?
He's lurking behind you.
저기요, 보스 / 왜 그래?
Hey, boss.
What?
어, 그냥 생각나서 하는 말인데
Well, I was, uh,
I was just thinking,
그게, 토니 선배가 한 주 쉬는 걸
정말 좋아했잖아요. 비숍과 제가 문제를...
you know, Tony's really excited
about having the week off.
Bishop and I can handle things
문제가 생겼어요 / 잘...?
just...
We have a problem.
...fine?
무슨? / 문제가 뭐야?
What's the problem?
해군 명부를 조회해봤는데 대니얼 하비
병장은 기록에서 찾을 수 없었어요
I checked the Navy Locator.
There's no listing for
a Petty Officer Daniel Harvey
anywhere in the Navy's record.
누가 이 사람에게 이야기를 해 줘야겠군
Someone needs to tell him that.
애비가 신분증을 점검해 봤어요
Abby examined the I.D.
이게 위조라면, 정말 잘 된 겁니다
If it's a forgery,
it's a really good one.
지문으로도 결과가 없고요
And no hits on his prints.
차량은 진짜에요. 국방부 보유 차량에 등록되어 있어요
Vehicle's legit--
it's registered
to the Department
of Defense's motor pool.
누가 가지고 나갔지? / 기록에는
아직 차고지에 있는 걸로 되어 있어요
Who checked it out?
According to their records,
it's still sitting
in the garage.
경비소에 있는 출차 기록을 볼 수 있을 거에요
There is an exit log at the
guard station we could look at.
제가 그건 해결할 수 있어요
I can handle that.
그러니까 바로 여기서, 지금
기록에 접근할 수 있어요
I mean, I can access that--
right here, right now,
in the database.
바로 하겠습니다
I'm gonna do that.
여자는?
The girl.
롤리타 코르테즈, 21세
Uh, Lolita Cortes, 21.
콜롬비아 출신이지만 18세
때 미국으로 이민왔습니다
Born in Colombia, but emigrated
to the U.S. when she was 18.
이민관세수사청(ICE)에 따르면
어제 밤 콜롬비아에서 돌아왔습니다
ICE has her coming back from
a trip to Colombia last night.
이틀동안 콜롬비아에 있었죠
She was there for two days.
이틀만에 다녀오기는 먼 거리인데요
That's a long trip
for just two days.
- 전과가 있나?
- 매춘으로 두 번 구속됐어요
Does she have a record?
She was arrested twice
for prostitution.
동업자 중 한 사람 말로는 포주와 사이가 틀어졌다고 해요
One of her coworkers said she
had a falling out with her pimp.
만약 지난 여섯 달 동안 고대해
왔던 여행을 떠날 비행기를 탈 필요가 없다면
If I didn't have a plane
to catch for a trip I'd been
- 거기를 가장 먼저 찾아봐야...
- 빨리 가 봐
forward to for the last six
months, that's the first place
I'd be looking-- hint, hint.
Go, go, go, go.
갑니다, 떠나요!
Going, gone!
재밌게 보내요! / 뭔가 찾았어요
Have fun!
Found something.
아마 굉장히 흥미로운 거겠지!
문자해 줘, 맥기. 범인이 누군지 알려줘
And I'm sure it's gonna be
very compelling!
Text me, McGee.
Let me know who the bad guy is.
국방부 차량 기록에서 자동차
징발 요구서를 찾았어요
Found a requisition
for the car
in a DoD motor pool database
접근 권한은 없지만 어쨌든 열어 봤는데
that I do not have access to,
but I accessed anyway.
이 차는 어떤 작전에서 징발했냐 하면...
Uh, car was
requisitioned to an op
"렉스... 탈리오나스(Lex Talionis)"?
called Lex... Talionis?
Uh...
무슨 일이죠? / 전혀 모르겠어
what just happened?
I have no idea.
Huh.
가서 알아보자고
Let's go find out.
"렉스 탈리오니스"가 뭔지 아세요?
You know what Lex Talionis is?
무슨 구절인지는 알아. 라틴어지
I know the phrase-- Latin.
뜻은, 복수의 법. 눈에는 눈
그런 뜻이야
It means, uh,
law of retaliation;
eye for an eye;
that kind of thing.
그런 이름의 작전은 알고 있어요? / 아니
Oh, you ever heard of
an op with that name?
No.
접근이 거부됐어
I'm locked out!
대체 무슨 일이죠? / 모르겠어
What the hell's going on?
I don't know.
깁스 요원, 무슨 말씀이신지 모르겠군요
Agent Gibbs, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
"렉스 탈리오니스" 작전에 배정된
차량에 탄 채 사망한 병장을 발견했습니다
We got a dead petty
officer driving
a vehicle assigned
to Lex Talionis.
이건 저희 작전입니다 / 어떻게 저희
요원이 모르는 작전활동이 있는 겁니까?
That's our op.
Why is there
operational activity
that my agents
aren't aware of?
밴스 국장님, 현장에서 "렉스 탈리오니스"
활동이 이뤄졌다면 저도 모르는 일입니다
Director Vance, if there's
Lex Talionis activity
in the field, then I'm
not aware of it, either.
드문 일도 아니죠. 이게 매우
개별화된 작전이라는 건 아실 겁니다
Which isn't unusual.
You do recall this is a highly
compartmentalized operation.
아직 책임자이신 겁니까?
Are you in charge or not?
불만이신 건 이해합니다. 이 작전에
오랫동안 참가해 오셨으니까요
I understand your frustration.
I know you've been working
on this for years.
그러니 집중하도록 하죠. 병장이 어디 소속이었나요?
So let's focus.
Where was the petty
officer assigned?
아직 알아보고 있습니다 / 해군 신분증은
있지만 어디에도 기록은 없더군요
We're still looking.
He had Navy I.D.
But there's no record of
him in any Navy database.
- 위장일 지도 모르죠
- 유출이 있는 걸까요?
Might be a cover.
Could we have
some kind of a leak?
만약 유출이 있고 우리가 목표를
추적하고 있다는 걸 알면 더 깊이 숨을 겁니다
Well, if there is and the target
finds out we're after him,
he'll go even
deeper underground.
그러면 수십년 만의 가장 좋은 기회를 놓치는 겁니다
And we lose the best shot we've
had at finding him in years.
알겠습니다. 조사를 계속해주세요
이 쪽에서도 할 수 있는 일을 찾아보겠습니다
Understood. Do your thing.
I'll see what I can
find out on my end.
해군 정보부의 카르솅크 연결해 줘
국무부의 에드먼즈 대사도
Get me Carschenk
at Naval Intelligence.
And Ambassador Edmunds at State.
깁스 요원, 나머지 팀을 데려올 때가 된 것 같네요
Agent Gibbs,
I think it's time to bring in
the rest of your team.
지금 보고 있는 영상이 어디죠?
So what exactly
are we looking at?
메트로폴리탄 국제 공항, 1979년
Metropolitan
International Airport.
1979.
누군가 출발 터미널에서 폭탄을 터트렸지
Someone detonated a bomb
in the departure terminal.
기억나네요. 당시에 몇 십년만에
미국 영토에서 가장 큰 공격 중 하나였죠
I know this.
At the time, it was
one of the deadliest attacks
on American soil in decades.
100명 가까운 사람이 다치거나 죽었지
Almost a hundred people
injured or killed.
누가 했나요?
Who did it?
아무도 몰라
Nobody knows.
미제 사건이 되고 공격은 일반인에게 잊혔지
VANCE: Case went cold
and the attack was
all but forgotten by the public.
- 하지만.. 우리는 일반인이 아니야
- 그리고 미합중국은 잊지 않으니까
But we... are not the public.
And the United States of America
doesn't forget.
단서를 찾으셨군요. 40여년이 지난
뒤에 단서를 찾으신 거군요
You got a lead.
After almost 40 years,
you got a lead.
2년 전, 콜롬비아의 NCIS 요원이
79년에 사용한 것과 놀랄 만큼 유사한
Two years ago,
NCIS agents in Colombia
recovered an unexploded bomb
사용하지 않은 폭탄을 발견했어
with a striking similarity
to the one used
at Metropolitan Airport in '79.
내부 부품의 접촉 DNS을 조사한 결과
두 폭탄 모두 같은 사람이 만들었다는 걸 확인했지
Touch DNA of the internal
components confirmed
that both bombs were made
by the same bomb maker.
Wow.
토니, 어째서 이런 걸 저는 모르고 있었던 거죠?
Tony, how exactly
do you know all this
and I don't?
타이슨 제독은 정보를 기밀로 분류하고
폭탄 제조자를 추적하는 비밀 작전을 만들었지
Admiral Tyson immediately
classified the Intel
and created a secret op
to track down the bomb maker.
작전명을 "렉스 탈리오니스"로 했군요
And she named the operation
Lex Talionis.
깁스 요원은 콜롬비아의 경험 때문에 지휘를 맡았지
Agent Gibbs was placed in charge
because of his prior
experience in Colombia.
토니는 참여시키고 저는 뺀 거군요
And he brought Tony in,
and not me.
저도요
Or me.
실은 그 때는 들어오기 전이어서 지바가 있었지
Actually you weren't here yet,
Ziva was.
이런, 지바도 알고 있었다는 거예요?
Oh, come on, you're telling me
that Ziva knew, too?
맥기 요원, 이 브리핑의 주제는
자네의 자존심이 아닐세
Agent McGee, your ego is not
the subject of this briefing.
그러면 무슨 주제인가요?
So, who is the subject?
토마스 올란도, 62세
Tom찼s Orlando...
62.
전 콜롬비아 반군 소속으로 지금은
가장 큰 마약거래상 중 하나지
He was formerly a
Colombian rebel, now he's
one of the country's
biggest drug kingpins.
6개월 전 용의자를 올란도로 좁혔지
We narrowed the
suspect pool down
to Orlando about
six months ago.
어떻게요? / 긴 이야기야, 비숍
How?
Well, it's a
long story, Bishop.
읽어 봐
Read up.
지난 6개월 간, 올란도가 범인인지
확인하기 위해 DNA 샘플을 얻으려 시도했어
For the past six months,
we've tried to get a DNA sample
from Orlando to confirm
that he's our guy.
찾기 쉬운 남자는 아니니까
성과는 없는 채였지
He's not an easy man to find.
We've been dead in the water.
지금까지는요? / 그걸 알아내야 하네
Until today?
That's what you need
to find out.
병장이 뭘 하고 있었는지는 몰라도
고대하던 돌파구가 있을지도 모르니까
Whatever's going on
with that petty officer,
this just might be the break
that we've been waiting for.
아무도 없나?
Hello?
애비?
Abby?
찾은 게 있다면서
Hear you got something.
왜? 무슨 일 있어?
What? Something wrong?
전혀요. 토니가 설명해 줬어요
Not at all.
Tony read me in.
콜롬비아에 있던 폭탄과 공항 폭발 미제사건의
DNA가 일치했다는 놀라운 소식을 들었어요
I heard the fantastic news
that you matched DNA
from the cold case
airport bombing
to a recent bomb in Colombia.
정말.. 놀라운 일이에요!
That is... awesome!
그래서? / 정말 놀랄 따름이에요
So?
So I'm just thrilled.
깁스를 위해 DNA를 돌려줄 사람이 있다는 거잖아요
You got someone to run
DNA for you.
관련 장비가 가득한 실험실의 누군가요
Someone with a lab full
of DNA-running equipment.
그런 사람을 안다는 건 정말 멋진 일일 거에요
I mean, it must be so cool
to know somebody like that.
- 애비, 그런 게 아니야
- 저를 속였어요, 깁스
Abby, it's not like that.
You cheated on me, Gibbs.
애비, DNA는 내가 배정받았을 때
동남부 현장 사무실에 보관되어 있었어
Abby, the DNA was
in the southeast field office
when I was assigned the op.
자네에게 가져다 주려면 너무 많은 손을 거쳤을 거야
It would've run through too many
hands to get up here to you.
좋아요, 이해할 수 있어요
Okay, that makes sense.
이상하지만...
Awkward... (anxious laugh)
- 그 대신 뭘 해 드리면 될까요?
- 뭘 알아냈나 말해봐
What can I do
to make it up to you?
Just show me what you got.
지나간 일로 하죠
Consider it done.
아니면 제가 끝났다고 할 때까지요
대충, 30초 정도 거릴 텐데요
Or consider it done
when I'm done,
which should take me,
like, 30 seconds.
좋아요, 범인에 대한 단서를 잡았어요
Okay, I got a lead
on our killer.
차에서 아름다운 인간성의 상징인
사람의 지문을 찾았어요
I found bloody fingerprints
in the car that belong to this
fine specimen of humanity.
에디 "칼라본" 로자리오
Eddie 쏞ollarbone Rosario.
제가 "포주"라는 말을 말을 한
것보다 더 많이 그 혐의로 잡혔어요
He's been busted
for pimping more times
than I've said
the word 쐏imping.
포주, 포주, 포주, 포주, 포주
Pimping, pimping, pimping,
pimping, pimping.
이제 똑같네요
Now we're tied.
피해자가 포주와의 관계가 틀어졌다고 하던데
Our victim said she had a
falling out with her pimp.
그렇다면 바로 이 사람이
그녀의 포주일 것 같네요
Well, then I would assume
that that is him.
그리고 시체가 생긴 거로 봐서
그 사람이 이긴 것 같네요
And judging by the dead bodies,
I think he won the argument.
이상하네. 비숍에게서 메신저가 왔어요
Weird.
Just got an IM from Bishop.
뭐라는데? / 제독님이 즉시 뵙고 싶어 하신대요
Yeah, what's it say?
The admiral needs
to see you right now.
이미 올라가고 계세요
Yeah.
He's already on his way.
얻은 정보가 뭔가요?
Okay, what do we have?
병장의 신원이죠. 콜롬비아 대사도 연결했어요
The identity
of our petty officer.
I've brought in
our ambassador to Colombia.
대사님도 새 정보가 있다고 하네요
She has news, as well.
에드먼즈 대사님 / 깁스 요원
드디어 직접 만나뵙게 되어 기쁘네요
Ambassador Edmunds.
Agent Gibbs,
nice to finally meet you
in person, as it were.
그래서, 이 사람이 누구죠?
So, who was he?
남성의 실제 이름은 루이스 프레스턴 대위입니다
TYSON: Well, our male
victim's real name
was Lieutenant Louis Freston.
아는 이름이군요. 정보 전문가로
최근에 배정되었죠
GIBBS:
I know the name.
Intelligence specialist.
Recently assigned.
아무래도 대위가 롤리타를 자원으로 잡은 모양입니다
Apparently he had cultivated
Lolita as an asset.
친척이 올란도의 머리를 자른다고 주장했거든요
She has relatives in Colombia
who claim to know
where our target
got his hair cut.
그런 보고는 주마다 두 번은 올라오지만
결실을 맺지는 못했죠
You know, we get a report
like this twice a week.
It never pans out.
이번에는 달랐어요
This one did.
프레스턴이 제출하려 했던 보고서에는
롤리타가 콜롬비아에서 모발 샘플을
The report Freston
was about to file
says Lolita was
bringing him a hair sample
주워서 가져 왔다고 적혀 있습니다
she'd picked up from Colombia.
살해당하던 날 밤에 주기로 되어 있었죠
She was going to give it to him
the night they were killed.
만약 DNA가 공항 폭탄과 일치한다면 범인을 찾는 거죠
And if his DNA matches
the DNA from the airport bomb,
we got our guy.
현장에서 모발 샘플은 찾지 못했습니다
We didn't find a hair sample
at the crime scene.
프레스턴의 기록에 따르면 창녀의
지갑 봉재선 안에 꿰매 두었다네요
According to Freston's notes,
it was sewn into the lining
of the prostitute's purse.
지갑은 찾지 못했습니다
We didn't find a purse.
보스, 그에 대한 단서가 있어요
길 건너편의 상점 주인이 영상을 찍었어요
Actually, boss, I may
have a lead on that.
A store owner across
the street shot video
총격 직후에요 / 한 번 보자고
on his cell,
just after the shooting.
Let's see it.
포주가 DNA를 갖고 있
Pimp has her DNA.
다시 가져오는 데 12시간 남았습니다
And you have 12 hours
to get it back.
별이 자리를 찾아가고 있습니다, 깁스 요원
The stars are aligning,
Agent Gibbs.
대사님? / 프레스턴의 행동이 이야깃거리를 불러왔어요
Ambassador?
EDMUNDS: Freston's play
kicked up some chatter.
올란도가 고위 간부들과 모임을 갖는다는 정보가 들어왔습니다
I just received Intel
on a meeting between Orlando
and his top lieutenants.
- 위치도 확보했고요
- SEAL 팀을 보내겠습니다
We have a location.
I'm scrambling a SEAL team.
올란도가 범인인지 확인해야 합니다
기회를 잡을 수 있을 때 말이죠
You need to verify
Orlando is our guy.
while we have a window
of opportunity.
지난 40년 간 가장 좋은 기회입니다
This is the best shot
we've had in 40 years.
알겠습니다
Understood.
이제 값아줄 때가 된 거죠
It's payback time.
McGee?
- 오, 깁스 요원님은 어디 있어?
- 총애하는 요원과 MTAC에 있지
Oh, hey!
Where's Agent Gibbs?
In MTAC with his favorite agent.
미안해. 뭐 먹을 시간이 없어서
I'm sorry. I didn't get
the chance to eat.
도움이 됐다니 다행이네
Happy to help.
유죄판결 받은 포주 에디
로자리오에 대해 지명수배를 내리고 싶은데요
McGEE:
Yeah, I need a BOLO out
on a convicted pimp
named Eddie Rosario.
길거리 이름은 칼라본이고요
Street name is Collarbone.
어.. 저기, 어떻게 해야?
Uh... excuse me,
how do I, uh...?
어떻게 하면 여기..?
Do you know how...?
초인종같은 게 있나?
Is there a doorbell
or something?
잠시만요, 혹시...?
Excuse me, do you...?
저기, 제가 투명인간인 것도 아니잖아요!
Okay, I'm not invisible, people!
좋아요, 저는 투명인간이 아니라고요!
All right, I'm not invisible!
무슨 일이야, 팔머?
TONY:
What do you want, Palmer?
카메라가 있구나 / 무슨 일이야, 팔머?
There is a camera.
What do you want, Palmer?
맬러드 박사님이 소식이 있대요, 큰 건으로요!
Dr. Mallard has news, big news!
I...
Uh...
(clears his throat)
(door opens)
맥기가 포주에게 지명수배를 내렸어요
McGee's got a BOLO
out on the pimp.
팔머가 문 앞에 있었고요
더키 박사님이 뭔가 찾았대요
That was Palmer
scratching at the door.
Ducky's got something.
화면에 띄워. 무슨 일이야, 덕
Hey, put him up on the screen.
Hello, Duck.
오, 원하면 이 짜증나는 걸 띄울 수 있다는 걸 잊고 있었군
Oh, I forgot you can
turn that damn thing on
whenever you want, can't you?
팔머 말로는 뭔가 찾았다면서?
Palmer said you had something?
검사 중에 여성의 둔부에서 작은 문신을 찾았네
Well, during my examination,
I found a small tattoo
on the young lady's derri챔re.
마치 없애려 한 것 같은 흔적이 있어서 좀 이상하게 생각했지만
It looked as if someone
had tried to scrape it off,
which I thought was a bit odd.
그래서 제가 찾아봤어요. 롤리타의 포주는
자신의 여자에게는 이런 낙인을 찍더군요
So, I ran it down.
Turns out Lolita's pimp
brands his girls
with that particular tattoo.
그래서 이 문신을 추적해 보니...
So, I was able to
track the art to...
토니에게 깁스 요원님께 할 말이 있다고 전했어요
I told Tony that you wanted
to speak to Agent Gibbs.
깁스 요원님이 직접 한 말은 아니지만요
Not that Gibbs
ever actually speaks.
"뭐 찾았지, 덕?" 하고 나면 제가 받은 건...
After 쏻hat do you got, Doc?
all I ever get is...
화난 시선 뿐이죠
angry glare.
안녕, 팔머
Hey, Palmer.
화난 시선
Angry glare.
포주가 여자들에게 낙인을 찍는데
문신 그림을 가지고 이런 걸 시술해 주는
Uh, pimp brands his girls,
and I was able to track
웹사이트를 찾았어요
the tattoo art to the Web site
of the parlor that does it.
잘 했어, 비숍 / 어쩌면 칼라본이
어디서 지내는지 단서를 찾을 수 있겠네요
Thanks, Bishop.
Yeah, may give us a lead
on where Collarbone hangs out.
좋아, 맥기랑 같이 가 보도록 해
All right, take, uh,
McGee with you, huh?
좋아, 맥기. 오는 동안 말 한마디도
앉고 있었는데 이야기나 들어 보자고
(laughs)
All right, McGee.
You've been pouting the whole
car ride-- let's hear it.
그러니까 2년 동안인 거죠? / 안 듣고 싶어졌어
So, two years, huh?
I don't want to hear it.
이 작전을 지난 2년 간 해 오면서 아무 말도 하지 않았군요
You've been working on
this op for two years
and never said anything.
그게 이건, 뭐라고 하지...
기밀 작전이었으니까
Well, it was, um...
what do you call it?
Oh, yeah! Classified.
오, 제가 기밀 작전 자료를 가져와서
공유한 적이 얼마나 돼요?
Oh, come on, how many
times have I hacked
classified data and
shared it with you?
47번 / 그래요. 그게...
47 times.
Yeah, it's...
그거 알아요? 그 정도 될 거에요
You know what?
That's probably right.
그래도 그게 내 주장의 요점이에요
But you proved my point.
그렇다 함은? / 더 이상 신용할 수가 없다는 거죠
Which is?
Can't trust you anymore.
깁스가 나는 끼워주고 너는 안 끼워준 데 분노하는 거잖아
(sighs) You're just upset
'cause Gibbs read me in and not you.
그런 거 아니에요
이유가 있을 거에요
That's not it at all, all right?
I'm sure he had his reasons.
아마도 잘못된 것이겠지만요
As misguided as
they probably were.
문신 작업장에 들어왔다는 첫 신호군
Sign number one you've walked
into the wrong tattoo shop.
고양이 오줌 냄새가 나는 거요?
그래
Smells like cat pee?
Yeah. (groans)
잠시만요! 피 나는 사람이 있어서요!
MAN:
Just a sec! Got a bleeder!
기다릴게요
We'll wait.
간염도 즐길 수 있으려면 좋으련만
Hope he enjoys the hepatitis.
그리고, 이 이야기 끝난 거 아니에요
Hey, we're not done
yet, by the way.
남은 이야기는 뭔데?
Well, what is left?
내가 먼저 들어왔고, 이제 너도 들어왔잖아
I was read in first.
And now you have been read in.
또 다른 비밀 작전을 하고 있을지 어떻게 알아?
How do I know you're not
working on another secret op?
또 다른 비밀 작전을 하고 있을지 어떻게 알아요?
How do I know you're not
working on another secret op?
다른 비밀 작전 하고 있어?
Are you working
on another secret op?
맥기! / 신경쓰이지 않나요?
McGee!
Hurts, doesn't it?
좋아, 의미가 있을는지는 모르겠지만
네게 거짓말 해서 기분이 나빴어
TONY: All right,
for what it's worth,
I felt bad lying to you.
즐겼던 것 같은데요 / 약간은
I think you enjoyed it.
A little bit.
전체적으로는 기분이 나빴어
But mostly I felt bad.
사과를 받아들이죠
Apology accepted.
(clears his throat)
두 분... 따로 시간을 보내게 해 드릴까요?
You two...
maybe want to be alone?
에드워드 로자리오?
Edward Rosario?
아무도 나를 에드워드라고 부르지 않아
칼라본이라고
Nobody calls me Edward.
It's Collarbone.
우리는 "아무나"가 아니니까
We're not 쐍obody.
(speaks Spanish)
드디어 차에서 내려서 다행이네요ㄴ
두 사람 노래 취향은 최악이었어요
Yeah, thank God
I'm out of that car.
You two have
the worst taste in music
I've heard in my life.
Ah!
포주를 찾았군요
You found the pimp.
밤에는 포주. 낮에는 문신 예술가
Pimp by night.
Tattoo artist by day.
지갑은요? / 트렁크에서 찾았어
The purse?
In his trunk.
봉재선에 DNA 튜브가 있어
애비에게 가져다줘야지
There was a DNA tube
sewn in to the lining.
I'm running it
down to Abby now.
보스에게 말해 둘게요 / 알겠어
I will brief Gibbs.
Okay.
상황 보고 바랍니다
Commander, give me a sitrep.
장병들은 배치되어 대기하고 있습니다
My men are deployed
and standing by.
개시 명령만 기다리고 있습니다
여기는 좀 긴장되네요
Just awaiting the go-order.
We're chomping at the bit here.
우리 모두 그렇습니다, 핸코스 사령관
We all are, Commander Hankos.
오래 기다리지 않아도 되겠어요
토니와 맥기가 포주를 찾았어요
Might not be much longer.
Tony and McGee
found the pimp.
목표물의 DNA을 찾았나?
They get our target's DNA?
지금 바로 토니가 애비에게 샘플을 가져다주고 있어요
Tony's bringing the sample
to Abby, as we speak.
올란도가 범인인 지 확인하는 데 오래 걸리지는 않을 겁니다
Shouldn't take her long to
verify that Orlando is our guy.
팀 위치는 얼마나 안전한가요?
How secure is
your team's position?
콜롬비아가 네이비 씰이 있기에
가장 안전한 곳은 아닙니다만, 해낼 겁니다
Colombia's not the safest place
for Navy SEALs
to hang out in,
but they'll make do.
알겠습니다 포주는 어디 있지?
Understood.
Where's the pimp?
맥기 선배가 취조실에 데려다 놨어요
McGee brought him
to interrogation.
- 올란도와 일한다고 생각하는 건가요?
- 가서 알아봐야죠
HANKOS: You think he's working
with Orlando?
We're gonna find out.
만약 그렇다면 협상도 형량 감형도 없어야 합니다
죄값을 치르게 해 줘야죠
If he is, no deals,
no plea bargains.
You make him pay.
사람들이 메트로폴리탄 공격을 잊었을 지 모르지만
저는 아닙니다
People may have forgotten
about the Metropolitan attack.
I haven't.
핸코스 사령관님이 잊지 않는다고요?
Commander Hankos
hasn't forgotten?
그 때라면 아직 어린아이셨을 텐데요
He must've been, like, a baby
when the attack happened.
그랬지. 사령관이 잊지 않은 건
그 사건으로 아버지 없이 자랐다는 거야
He was.
What he hasn't forgotten
was growing up without a father,
because of it.
(sighs)
사령관이 작전을 지휘할 확률이 얼마나 될까요?
What are the odds he'd be
the one commanding this mission?
가능할 만큼 높지. 이 작전 지휘에 자원했어
About as good as it gets.
He asked to command
this mission.
죄값을 치를 때가 되면 사령관이
수표에 서명하고 싶어 했으니까
When it's time for payback,
he wants to be the one
to write the check.
나도 그가 어떤 기분일 지 알고
And I know exactly how he feels.
(sighs)
앉아
Sit down.
앉지 않겠다면 내가 앉혀 주지
Sit down or I'll sit you down.
(laughs)
그런다고 무서워할 것 같아
You don't scare me.
손이라도 대면...
You lay one hand on me,
and... (chuckles)
계속 해 봐
Go on.
기다리지, 말을 끝까지 해 봐
I'll wait. Finish.
좋아
Fine.
앉아줄 수야 있지. 그렇게 엉덩이에 집착한다면야
Sitting works, if you want
to be all anal about it.
- 토마스 올란도와 일한지는 얼마나 됐지?
- 누구?
How long you been working
for Tom찼s Orlando?
Who?
이걸 보면 생각이 좀 나나?
That jog your memory?
아니
Nah.
그녀를 죽이고 소지품을 들고 갔잖아
You killed her
and you took something from her.
뭔 약을 하는지는 모르겠지만 전혀 모르겠는데
I don't know what
you're smoking,
but I'd like a hit.
지갑에 있던 DNA 샘플을 가져갔잖아. 왜지?
The DNA sample that
was in her purse.
And you took it. Why?
DNA, 이런! DNA!
DNA에 대한 건 전혀 몰라
(laughs)
DNA, man! DNA!
I don't know anything
about no-no DNA.
내가 DNA 가 뭔지 알 사람으로 보여?
Do I look like a DNA
kind of guy to you?
가석방 없는 수감자로 보이는데
You look like a life
without parole
kind of guy.
네 타이어 자국을 범죄 현장에서 발견했어
I got your vehicle's tire tracks
at the crime scene.
피해자에게서 피묻은 지문도 발견했고
Got your bloody prints
on the victim.
좋아요, 잠깐만
Okay, wait a second here.
DNA! 말해 봐
DNA! Talk.
이봐요, 아까 말했잖아요
대체 무슨 말인지...
Hey, look, I already told you.
I don't know what you...
- 누가 샘플을 가져와달라고 했지?
- 대체 무슨 말인지 전혀 모르겠어요!
Who told you to take
that sample?
I don't know
what you're talking about!
좋아요. 난...
Okay, I...
난 낮에는 문신 가게를 해요
밤에는 그게...
I manage a tattoo parlor
during the day, okay?
But at night, I-I-I...
소규모로 프리랜스 에스코트 서비스를 하죠
I run this small
freelance escort service.
포주잖아 / 좋아요. 현실적으로 말하자면요
You're a pimp.
Okay, semantics.
어쨌든.. 롤리타는 내 여자 중 하나였어요
Anyways...
Lolita was one of my girls.
그러다 지난 주에 이제 나가겠다는 거에요!
Then, last week,
she tells me she's out!
말도 안 되는 소리죠
칼라본 밑에서 그만둘 수는 없어요
Nah. No.
No one quits Collarbone, no.
그런데 지난 밤에 그녀가 제 구역에서
일하는 걸 봤어요
Then, last night,
I find out she's
일하는 여자들에게 메시지를 전해야 했어요
working my turf, I-I... I got to
send a message to my girls, man.
그래서 죽였다고? / 명성이 없다면
남자는 아무 것도 아니거든요
So, you kill her?
A man's got nothing...
if he doesn't have
his reputation.
DNA는 왜 가져갔지?
Why'd you take the DNA?
DNA요? DNA는 뭔 소린지 전혀 모르겠어요!
아까도 말했잖아요!
The DNA? I don't know
anything about no DNA, man!
I told you!
지갑은 가져갔지만 그게 다에요!
I took her purse and that's all!
그 날 그녀가 번 건 내가 가져야 하니까요!
Because whatever bank
she made that night was mine!
분배는 확실하게 해야 하니까요
I mean, fair's fair, right?
말이 통할 것 같은데 말이죠
You seem reasonable.
(door opens)
규칙 22번 위배해서 죄송하지만
올론도 DNA를 돌렸는데 결과가...
Hi. Apologies to
Rule 22, Gibbs,
but I finished running
Orlando's DNA and...
우리가 찾는 사람이예요!
준비 태세인가요, 사령관?
곧 준비될 겁니다
Are your men
in position, Commander?
They will be in half a mike.
어디 있죠? 아무도 안 보이는데요
BISHOP:
Where are they?
I don't see anyone.
배치되어 있습니다 / 현지인들 소문은 어떤가요?
They're there.
Any chatter from the locals?
없어
Nothing.
습격 시작한다. 습격을 시작한다
We are a go for takedown.
Takedown is a go.
알겠다. 진입하겠다
SQUAD LEADER:
Roger. Copy that. Move in.
헬멧 카메라로 바꿉니다
Switching to helmet cams.
후문으로 들어갑니다
SQUAD LEADER:
Breaching the back entrance.
이상 없음
Clear.
흩어져, 계속 살펴봐
Fan out. Loop around.
이상 없음
Clear!
Clear.
사령관님, 목표물이 없습니다
Commander,
the target not present.
건물은 비어 이습니다
The building has been vacated.
정보는 정확한 거였습니다
The Intel our office received
was good.
올란도가 21시에 고위 간부와 이 건물에서
모임을 가질 거라는 거였죠
Orlando had a confirmed meeting
with his top lieutenants
in the building at 2100 hours.
아무래도 취소된 것 같군요
It looks like he canceled.
어떠면 습격에 대해 알았을 수도 있습니다
VANCE: He could have
found out about the assault.
콜롬비아 정부에 작전을 통보했습니까?
Did you alert
the government of Colombia
that we were making a play?
부적절한 말입니다만, 정신이 있다면 그랬겠습니까?
With all due respect,
are you out of your mind?
핸코스 사령관이 연결을 기다리고 있습니다
Uh, boss, we've got
Commander Hankos on the line.
연결해
Patch him in.
벌써 담당 반대쪽에서 전화가 걸려와서는
EDMUNDS:
I'm already getting
screaming phone calls
from my counterpart,
미국이 콜롬비아 영토에서 작전을
수행 중인지 물어보고 있습니다
wondering if the U.S.
is running an op
on sovereign Colombian soil.
사령관, 상황은 어떤가?
Commander,
what's your status?
델타 쿼드란드 위치를 고수하고 있습니다
HANKOS:
My men are holding position
in the Delta Quadrant.
현지민이 공격을 시작해서
올란도의 건물에서 나와야 했습니다
They started taking fire
from some locals,
so we had to pull back
from Orlando's compound.
그렇다면 작전을 취소할 것을 추천하는 건가요?
Is it your recommendation, then,
that we abort the mission?
아닙니다. 그 장소는 급하게 비워졌어요
Hell, no. Place was
cleaned out in a hurry.
바로 근처에 있는 겁니다
We're right on his tail.
건물에서 쓸만한 정보는 찾았나?
You get any useful Intel
from the compound?
반쯤 부서진 노트북을 찾았는데
하드 디스크는 붙어 있습니다
We recovered a partially
destroyed laptop,
but the hard drive's
still intact.
- 목표를 추적할 만한 단서는 있나요?
- 모릅니다. 암호화되어 있어서요
Anything there we could use
to track the target?
Unknown.
It was encrypted.
저희 기술자가 접근하려 하고 있습니다
My tech's still trying
to access it.
- 사령관님, 애비 슈토와 제가 더 운이 있을지도 모릅니다
- 시도해볼 수 는 있지만 DC로 노트북을 보내는 데는
Commander, Abby Sciuto and I
might have some better luck.
You're welcome to try,
but it'll take
12시간이 걸릴 텐데 그만한 시간은 없습니다
at least 12 hours
to get that laptop to DC.
My men don't have
that kind of time.
저희 쪽 사람이 만나러 가면 됩니다
Our people can meet.
무슨 말씀이시죠?
Meaning what?
- 사령관의 항모는 걸프 만에 있어
- 애비에게 말하러 가겠습니다
The commander's
aircraft carrier in the Gulf.
I'll... run down
to tell Abby.
그 동안 콜롬비아 영사에는 뭐라고 말하죠?
In the meantime, what do I tell
the Colombian ambassador?
외교관이시니 / 외교적인 수사를 써 보세요
You're a diplomat.
Say something diplomatic.
타이밍이 좋네
Nice timing.
내가 먼저 말할게
Me first.
애비 먼저, 말해 봐
Abby first. Go.
올란도의 최근 DNA 샘플에서
두 번째 일치자를 찾았어요
I got a second hit
on the most recent
DNA sample from Orlando.
친족 간 일치요
It's a familial match.
누구? / 볼티모어 외각에 있는
조카가 있어
Who?
He has a niece that lives
outside Baltimore.
어쩌면 삼촌과 연락하는지도 모르겠네
Well, she may be in
contact with the uncle.
올란도가 어디 있는지 알 지도 몰라
Maybe she knows
where he is.
앱스, 잘 했어. 이제 짐을 싸도록 해
Abbs, good work.
Now go pack your bags.
어딜 가는데요?
Where am I going?
애비가 올란도의 친척을 찾았다는데
Hey. Abby found a relative.
이미 들었어요. 친척의 이름은
수잔나 소토 박사예요
We heard.
Relative's name
is Dr. Susanna Soto.
로즈데일에서 가족 테라피 치료를 하고 있죠
Runs a family therapy practice
in Rosedale.
- 여기에 얼마나 있었지?
- 미국에서 태어났어요
How long she been here?
She was born in the States.
DNA 관계로는 그녀의 아버지와
올란도는 형제 관계였어요
Going by DNA, her father
and Orlando were brothers.
관계였다고? / 예. 그녀의 아버지는
그녀가 7세 때 살해당했어요
Were?
Yeah, her parents were killed
when she was seven.
외가에서 자랐죠
Raised by her mother's family.
삼촌을 알고나 있는지도 확실할 수 없어요
We don't even know
if she knows her uncle.
- 콜롬비아와이 접촉은 있나?
- 유무선 전화로는 없어요
Any contact with anyone
in Colombia?
Nothing on her cell
or landline.
이메일은? / 적어도 주 계정은요
저희가 모르는 다른 계정이 있을 수도 있지만요
E-mail.
Not on her main account,
but she could have others
we don't know about.
확실히 하려면 직접 컴퓨터에 접근해야 해요
We would need physical access
to her computer to be certain.
영장은 받았지만 몰려가면
올란도가 미행하고 있을지도 몰라요
TONY: We already got a warrant,
but if we go in heavy,
조사가 발각될지도 모르죠
the uncle could be watching--
might tip him off.
어떻게 할까요? 오랫동안 심문할 수도 없고
잘못된 정보를 받을 우려도 있어요
What's the play? There's no time
for a lengthy interrogation,
and we risk getting bad Intel
if we turn the screws.
이걸로 접근하면 되겠군
That's the play.
오, 부모 역할을 하겠군
Aw. We're gonna be parents.
보스, 잘 들리세요? / 선명하네
TONY:
Boss, you reading us?
Loud and clear.
좋아요. 그래서, 계획이 뭐지 비숍?
All right.
So, what's the plan, Bishop?
들어가서 앉은 뒤에 화장실에 간다고 하고
BISHOP:
We go in, get settled.
Then I excuse myself
to use the bathroom,
소토 박사의 PC에 접근해
여기에 하드 내용을 복사하는 거죠
I find Dr. Soto's PC
and mirror her hard drive
onto this.
완벽해
Perfect.
아내 먼저 / 고마워, 자기
Wives first.
Thanks, honey.
들어오세요. 여기 뒤쪽에 있어요
SOTO:
Come on in.
We're back here.
어서 들어오세요
Please come in.
Join us.
(chuckles softly)
안녕하세요
Oh. Hi.
Uh... (chuckles)
여기가 부모 수업이라고 했던가?
Um, is this
the parenting class?
죄송해요. 웹사이트에 착오가 있어서요
Oh, I'm sorry.
There was a mix-up
on the Web site.
오늘 밤은 커플 친밀감 수업이예요
Tonight is my
couples intimacy class.
Oh.
이거 흥미롭겠군
Well, this should
be interesting.
거짓말 했어, 그게...
솔직히 말하는 게 무서워서
TONY:
I lied. I was a...
afraid to tell
you the truth.
그게... 솔직히 말하면 같이 안 올 것 같아서
(chuckles) Because...
I-I didn't think
you would come.
알겠어요. 하지만 알아두셔야 할 건
친밀감의 첫걸음은 신뢰라는 겁니다
SOTO:
Oh, I see.
But you must
understand,
the first ingredient
for intimacy is trust.
일단 앉으세요
SOTO:
Please sit down.
알겠어요. 이 멋진 깔개의 촉감을 알아볼까
TONY: All right, let's check out
these cool pillows.
편안하네
Comfy.
(grunts, laughs)
SOTO:
Uh...
- 왜 두 분 다 앉지 않으시나요
- 저기, 화장실 좀 갈까 해서요
why don't you both sit down?
Actually, I have to use
the restroom.
이미 왔으니, 여기 같이 있으세요
Please.
You're here, so be here.
하지만 / 앉으세요
부탁할게
But I really...
Sit.
Please.
좋아요
Okay.
(quietly):
Thank you.
이제, 손을 잡으세요 / 예?
Now, take his hands.
Huh?
이런. 정말로 최근에 감기가 나아서...
Oh, gosh. For real, I-I'm
actually getting over a cold.
- 손, 잡으세요
- 발을 잡는 것보다야 낫지
Hands-- out.
Guess that's better
than my feet.
(awkward laughter)
이제 서로의 눈을 바라보세요
Now, look into his eyes...
(mouthing)
이런. 더 보고 있을 수가 없군
Ah, geez.
I can't watch this.
- 좋아요. 그 다음에는요?
- 아뇨, 계속 바라보고 계세요
Okay. Now what?
No. Don't break eye contact.
이제는요? / 계속 바라보세요
BISHOP:
So, now what?
Just keep looking.
산재 보상 서류가 올라오겠군
He's going to file
for hazard pay.
Whoa.
테일후크 착륙은 인생에서 가장
멋진 일이라고 생각해
Okay... tailhooking
is the coolest thing
I have ever done
in my life.
팬다 껴안기는 이걸로 끝이네
Well, so much
for hugging a panda.
맥기 요원, 슈토 양
와 주셔서 감사합니다
Agent McGee, Ms. Sciuto,
glad you could make it.
- 따라오세요. 시간이 촉박합니다
- 올랜도 노트북 쪽은 진척이 있나요?
Follow me.
We're tight on time.
Any progress
accessing Orlando's laptop?
구드 하사가 설명해 줄 겁니다
I'll let Petty Officer
Goode fill you in.
안녕하세요. 저는.. / 맥기 요원님이시죠
Hi. I'm...
Yeah, yeah, yeah, Agent McGee.
오시느라 시간만 낭비하신 겁니다
이미 노트북 접근에는 성공했으니
You wasted your time
coming here.
I was able to access
the laptop on my own,
다시 본부로 돌아가시는...
so you might as well
get back on your...
your, uh...
애비 슈토군요
You're Abby Sciuto.
그쪽은... 구드 하사군요
And you're...
Petty Officer Goode.
제 룸메이트 형제의 절친과 데이트하셨죠
아마 11년 전에요
You dated my roommate's
brother's best friend,
like, 11 years ago.
- 와. 기억력이 정말 좋으시네요
- 기억에 남을 만한 분이시니까요
Wow.
You have a really good memory.
You're kind of memorable.
음.. 그래서 노트북에 접근하셨다고요
ABBY:
Um...
uh, so you accessed the laptop.
예 / 그래서...?
Yeah.
And...?
이미 알고 있었던 올랜도의
만남에 대한 구체적인 정보를 찾았습니다
Oh, and I found
the details to the meeting
on Orlando's compound
that we already knew about.
그게 다예요 / 저희가 직접 살펴봐도 될까요?
That was about it.
Okay. Do you mind if we
take a look ourselves?
아니, 잠시만요. 11년 전이라고 했나요?
Uh, hold on--
one second.
Did you say 11 years ago?
아니 / 예
No.
Yeah.
제 룸메이트 형제의 절친이
커피숍 "Buzzed"에서 바리스타로 일했을 때였죠
Uh, my roommate's
brother's best friend
was a barista at this
coffeehouse called Buzzed.
"Buzzed"라. 우리도 잘 아는 곳이네
Oh, Buzzed.
Hey, we know that well.
거기 자주 갔었잖아, 11년 전에
I used to take you there
all the time, 11 years ago.
Oh.
(chuckling):
- 그래서 두 분은...?
아뇨 / 아뇨
So, are the two of you...
No.
ABBY:
Uh...
그건 무슨 뜻이야?
(sighs)
(sighs) What was that?
그게, 너는 형제같은 존재였고..
나도 알아. 나도 너를 자매처럼 생각했지만
I mean, you know, you're...
you're like my brother and...
Yeah, I know,
you're like my sister,
그렇게 표현하지는 않았어. 제발
but I wouldn't (sighs) you
like that. Come on.
- 이제 어떻게 된 영문이지 알겠네요
- 뭘 알겠다는 건가?
(chuckling):
Oh. Okay, now I get it.
What do you get?
바리스타한테 여자를 뺏긴 거군요
바로 코 앞에서요
You got dogged by the barista.
Right under your nose.
저기, 그냥 일이나 하면 안 될까요?
Uh, could we just please
get to work and...?
그게... / 애비, 걱정하지 마
이미 옛날 일인데. 괜찮아
I mean, it was...
Abby, don't worry about it.
It's ancient history.
It's fine.
이봐요. 애비 슈토가 일을 해야 한다고
하니 그렇게 하는 게 어떨까요?
Listen, you,
our friend Abby Sciuto
here said that we need
to get to work, so...
how about we do that?
좋아요. 그런 일을 잊고 싶을 때는
일하는 게 최고니까요
Yeah, uh...
if I let that one get away,
I'd bury myself in my work, too.
아니면 술을 마시거나요
Or start drinking.
(laughs) My lady.
위장 작전은 어떻게 됐나? / 노코멘트입니다
Oh. How did your
undercover op go?
No comment.
샤워라도 해야겠어요
(sighs)
I need a shower.
Oh... (chuckles)
- 누가 보스에게 브리핑하죠?
- 나는 아니야. 시간을 좀 가져야겠어
So, uh, who's briefing Gibbs?
Not me.
I need a moment.
뭐 때문에요? / 나한테 친밀감 문제가 있는지도 몰라
For what?
I may have intimacy issues.
오늘 밤은 그들에게 고마워해야겠네요
Well, tonight,
I was thankful for them.
- 올랜도의 노트북에서 뭔가 찾았나요?
- 맥기 요원이 한 시간은 더 필요하답니다
Our people having any luck
with Orlando's laptop?
Agent McGee said
they'll need another hour.
시간이 빡빡해지고 있어요 / 친족과
접촉한 요원 쪽은 어떻게 됐나요?
It's getting tight.
What about the agents
who made contact with
the family member?
비숍 / 드디어 화장실 가는 허락을 받아서..
Bishop.
I finally got permission
to use the restroom...
- 올란도와 연락을 하고 있나?
- 알아내는 데는 시간이 걸릴 거예요
Is she talking to Orlando?
It's going to take
some time to find out.
본인에게도 문제가 좀 있어서요
전자자료를 쌓아두는 습관이 있네요
She's got some issues
of her own.
She's a cyber-hoarder.
PC에 지난 30년간의 자료가 있어요
전부 돌리는 데 몇 주는 걸릴 겁니다
She's got three decades
of files on her PC.
It could take weeks
to run it all down.
그만한 시간은 없네
We don't have weeks.
올란도가 네이비 SEAL이 자기
건물에 들어갔다는 걸 곧 알게 될 겁니다
Just a matter of time
before Orlando
finds out Navy SEALs
were in his compound.
그러면 잠수를 타고 다시는 올라오지 않겠죠
Then he goes down and
never comes back up again.
이번 기회에 그를 찾지 못하면
영원히 놓치는 겁니다
We either find this guy
this go-around
or we could lose him forever.
- 올란도를 찾았습니다
- 어디 있어?
Found him.
Where?
스쿼드 실에요 / 어디라고?
스쿼드 실에 있습니다
Squad room.
In the where?
Squad room, ma'am.
안녕하시오
내가 토마스 올란도입니다
Hello.
I am Tom찼s Orlando.
미합중국에 망명을 신청하고 싶습니다
I am seeking asylum from
the United States of America.
(door opens)
규정에 따라 국무부에 알렸습니다
국무부에서는 그대로 인용하자면
Per regulations, I notified
State of his asylum request.
They wanted
to know, quote,
"대체 어떻게 국경을 넘었는지"
알고 싶어하더군요
쐆ow the hell
he got through customs.
전문 마약 밀수꾼이니까
국경선에서 줄 서고 있지는 않았겠지
Well, he's a professional
drug smuggler.
I doubt he
waited in line.
무슨 속셈일까요? / 속셈이 뭐건간에
강단이 있다는 건 인정해야겠어
What's he up to?
Well, whatever it is,
he's got a pair,
I'll give him that.
이제 어떻게 하죠? / 우리에게 왔으니
이유를 들어 봐야지
So what's the play?
He came to us.
Let's go find out.
- 국무부와 이야기를 해 봤다고 생각해도 되겠습니까?
- 그렇게 기대하지 않는 게 좋아요
May I assume you've spoken
to your State Department?
(Tony scoffs)
I wouldn't hold
my breath.
망명은 원래 그런 사람들에게 주는 게..
그걸 뭐라고 하죠?
Asylum isn't really
for, um...
What do they call
it again?
그래요, 테러리스트
Oh, yeah, terrorists.
- 나는 자유를 위한 투쟁가입니다
- 당신은 살인자고 마약 거래상입니다
I'm a freedom fighter.
You are a murderer
and a drug dealer.
미국이 잘못된 쪽에 무기를 공급하지 않으면
내 목표를 위해 마약을 팔 필요도 없었겠죠
Maybe if your country
stopped giving weapons
to the wrong team,
I wouldn't have to sell drugs
to finance my cause.
- 오 그래요? 목표가 있는 겁니까?
- 정의죠
Oh, really?
You got a cause?
Justice.
부패한 정부를 대신해서요
From a corrupt government.
정부에 반대했기 때문에
나를 몇 십년 간 감금해 둔 겁니다
A government which has
imprisoned me for decades
because I stood up to it.
- 그러면 이제는 여기서 몇 십년간 감금되겠군요
- 나는 공항 공격과 관련이 없습니다
So now you're going to be
in prison here, for decades.
I had nothing to do
with that airport attack.
전혀요 / 그거 흥미롭네요
DNA는 다르게 말하고 있는데요
Nothing.
That's interesting.
Your DNA was
on the bomb, pal.
당신네들이 갖고 있는 DNA는 내 것이 아닙니다!
함정에 빠진 거라고요
Whatever DNA you
have is not mine!
I'm being set up.
말해 봐요
Talk.
미국 정부에서 내 DNA 샘플을 가져가고
싶어한다는 걸 몇 달 전부터 알고 있었습니다
I've known for months
the United States
government was trying
to get a sample
of my DNA.
다만 이유를 몰랐죠. 적어도 당신네
정보원이 사살되기 전까지는요
I just didn't know why.
At least not until your
informant was killed.
그 여자... 여자의 가족들이 보호를
요청하며 내게 찾아왔습니다
The girl...
her family came to
me for protection.
모든 걸 말해 줬죠. 그 때 내가
함정에 빠졌음을 깨달았습니다
They told me everything.
That's when I realized
I was being framed.
메트로폴리탄 공항 폭탄테러와는 전혀
관계가 없어요. 전혀요
I had nothing to do with
the Metropolitan bombing.
Nothing to do with it.
흥미롭네요
그걸 직접 말하려고 여기까지 온 겁니까?
Fascinating.
So you just decided
to pop up north here
and tell us that in person?
가족이 있기 때문에 여기까지 온 겁니다
당신네 카우보이들 일하는 방식은 익히 알죠
I came here because
I have a family.
And I know how
you cowboys work.
일단 쏘고 질문은 그 다음이지요
Shoot first,
ask questions later.
내 아이들은, 내가 세운 왕국보다
훨씬 중요합니다
My children...
are more important to me
than my entire empire.
학교에서 돌아오다가 크루즈미사일에
맞는 위험을 감수하고 싶지는 않았습니다
I'm not willing to risk them
getting cruise-missiled
coming home from
school one day.
내 자식들이 드론을 찾기 위해 하늘을
훑는 법 대신 읽는 법을 배웠으면 합니다
I want them to
learn how to read,
not how to scan the skies,
looking for drones.
그러니..
So...
당신들이 이겼어요
You win.
- 이런 식으로 말이죠
- 어차피 이제 은퇴하려 했어요
Just like that.
I was retiring anyway.
당신들이 습격하려고 했던 모임에서 발표하려고 했어요
I was announcing it at that
meeting you tried to crash.
당신이 나를 믿지 않는 것도 보입니다
And I can see that
you don't trust me.
좋은 점은, 믿을 필요가 없다는 겁니다
The beauty is...
you don't need to.
직접 확인해 봐요
See for yourself.
나는 그 폭탄을 만들지 않았습니다
I didn't make that bomb.
누군지는 몰라도 당신이 쫒고 있다는 걸
알아채고는 갖고 놀고 있는 겁니다
Whoever did found out
that you're after him...
...and he is playing you.
마치 갈대처럼요
He's playing you like a fiddle.
서랍에서 안내서를 찾았어요
애비가 말한 대로요
JIMMY: Found the instruction
book in the drawer.
Just like Abby said.
여기 올랜도의 DNA가 있지
I have Orlando's DNA.
공항 폭탄범과 일치하는지 맞춰 보자고
Let's see if we
can match it
to the original
airport bomb.
캐프-파우가 필요한 거 아닌가 모르겠어요
잘 하실 수 있겠어요?
Maybe you guys need a Caf-POW.
Are you sure
you can handle this?
물론이지
안내서 줘 보게, 팔머 군
DUCKY:
Absolutely.
The instruction manual,
please, Mr. Palmer.
이 건은 제가 주도적으로 해야 하지 않을까요, 박사님?
Don't you think
that I should probably take
the driver's seat
on this one, Doctor?
주도적으로? / 부검과는 다르니까요
랩 훈련은 제가 더 다양하게 했고요
Driver's seat?
This is an autopsy-- I do have
more extensive lab training.
- 오, 그런가
- 이런, 싸우지 마세요. 여러분
Oh, really?
Oh, come now, gentlemen.
No need to fight.
법의학 수업을 최고 성적으로 졸업했다네
I graduated
with top honors
from my class of Forensics
- 에딘버러 대학에서 말이지
- 예. 하지만 그건 192...
at, uh, the University
of Edinburgh.
Yes, in nineteen-twenty...?
그만 해, 짐보 / 말이 그렇다는 거예요
Pull up, Jimbo.
I'm just saying.
그렇다면 NCIS에서 앞으로 부검실
바닥의 내장을 계속 치우고 싶다는 건가?
That you wish to be
cleaning intestines
off the autopsy floor
for the remainder
of your tenure at NCIS?
그건 협박처럼 들리는데요, 박사님
That sounded
like a threat, Doctor.
그렇다면 내 영어 실력도 시간의
풍파에도 무뎌지지 않은 모양이군
Well, apparently, my command
of the English language
has not been dulled by
the ravages of time.
내 읽기 능력도 말이지
Nor my ability to read.
놓아 줘, 엘사
Let it go, Elsa.
하실 말씀이 있으시다고요, 영사님?
그래요. 콜롬비아 정부에 던질 변명도 다 떨어졌어요
You wanted to speak
with me, Ambassador?
Yes, I'm running out of lies to
tell the Columbian government.
뭔가 있다는 걸 눈치챘어요
They know we're up to something.
이제 그건 중요치 않습니다
It's a moot point now.
NCIS가 목표물을 확보했다는 소식을 듣고
요원들은 탈출 지점으로 철수하고 있습니다
My men are pulling back
to the extraction point
since NCIS has
the target in custody.
확보했다고요? 언제요?
In custody?
Since when?
컨퍼런스 중이실 때 자수했습니다
상황이 유동적이니까요
He turned himself in
while you were in conference.
It's a fluid situation.
- 자신이 함정에 빠졌다고 주장했습니다
- 이제 주장이 아니예요. 정말 함정에 빠졌어요
He claims that he's been set up.
It's not a claim.
He was set up.
올랜도는 범인이 아닙니다. DNA가
공항 폭탄의 샘플과 일치하지 않습니다
Orlando's not our guy.
His DNA does not match the
sample from the airport bomb.
누가 누명을 씌운 거죠 / 확실한가요?
현재까지는요
Someone tried to frame him.
Are you sure?
As it gets.
그러면 얻은 게 없군요
다시 40년 전 원점으로 돌아간 셈이네요
So we have nothing.
We're back to 40 years ago.
아뇨. 성과는 있습니다. 범인이
아직 살아있다는 걸 알았죠
No... no, we have something.
We know the bomber's
still alive.
12시간 전 범인은 자신의 머리를 뽑아
올란도에게 누명을 씌우려 했습니다
12 hours ago, he used DNA
off his own head
to try and frame Orlando.
콜롬비아 측에서 우리가 수행한
침입을 알게 된다면 군을 최고 경계 태세로 돌릴 겁니다
EDMUNDS: When the Columbians
realize just what kind
of incursion we've committed,
they'll place their military
on high alert.
만약 팀을 다시 투입해야 한다면
빨리 결정해야 합니다
If I'm gonna reactivate my team,
we're gonna need something fast.
그렇다면 맞는 장소에 오신 겁니다
Well, I guess you've come
to the right place.
아니면.. 제가 말이죠
Or... I have.
안녕하세요, 깁스. 밴스 국장님
그리고 버튼 조작하시는 여러분
Hi, Gibbs.
Hi, Vance.
Hi, other people
pushing buttons
and stuff.
- 앱스, 뭘 알아냈어?
- 깁스, 키값 로거를 찾았어요
Abbs, what do you got?
A keystroke logger, Gibbs.
올랜도의 노트북에 붙어 있는 걸 맥기가 찾았어요
McGee found it embedded
on Orlando's laptop.
누군가 지난 몇 주간 그를 감시하고 있었어요
Someone has been spying
on him for weeks.
잘 했어, 하지만 올랜도는 더 이상
우리 추적 목표가 아니야
Good work, but Orlando's
no longer our target.
감청기 반대쪽에는 누가 있지?
Well, who was on the other
side of that bug?
국무부 IP 주소까지 추적했어요
에드먼즈 대사님?
Um, I traced it back to
a State Department IP address.
Ambassador Edmunds...?
올랜도의 컴퓨터에 몇 주 전부터
접근하셨으면서 저희에게는 말씀하지 않으신 겁니까?
You had access to Orlando's
computer for weeks,
and you neglected
to tell us?
뭐라고 하셨죠? 연결이 끊기네요
I'm sorry, what
did you say?
The connection's
getting fuzzy.
국무부 연결해. 비상상황이라고 말하고
VANCE: Get me the
Secretary of State.
Tell him it's
an emergency.
최대한 빨리 이야기해야 한다고 전해
I need to speak with him
as soon as possible.
국무부 보안국에 연락해서 에드먼즈
대사 관련한 상황이 발생했다고 전해
Call Diplomatic Security
at Foggy Bottom, tell him
that we have a situation
with Ambassador Edmunds.
헌병이 주차장에서 그녀를 확보했습니다
그리고는 자수했죠
MPs caught up with her
in the parking lot.
Turned herself in.
- 보스와 이야기를 나누고 싶다는군요
- 나도 그렇지
Says she wants
to talk to you.
Yeah, well,
feeling's mutual.
- 협상을 하고 싶습니다
- 물론 그렇겠죠
I want to make a deal.
Oh, I'll bet you do.
시간 별로 없습니다. 잘 아실 텐데요
We don't have much time,
you know that.
- 대체 무슨 일인지 말해 보세요
- 협상 없이는 안 됩니다
Tell me what's going on.
Not without a deal.
테러범을 보호하고 계신 겁니다
말하시면, 도와줄 방법을 찾아보죠
You're protecting
a terrorist.
Talk, and I will see
if I can help.
협상안을 제시하지는 않을 테니까요
They will never
give you a deal.
올랜도의 노트북에 접근할 방법을 줬습니다
그가 있는 장소를 제공했고요
Someone gave you access to
the bug on Orlando's laptop.
You fed us his location.
올랜도에게 누명 씌우는 걸 도운 겁니다
누구 밑에서 일하시는 겁니까?
You helped set him up.
Who are you working for?
누구 밑에서 일하는 건 아니예요
I'm not working for anybody.
적극적인 협력자가 아닙니다
협박을 받은 거라고요
I'm not a willing
accomplice.
I was threatened.
누구에게요?
By who?
35년 전, 그는 공산주의 혁명 그룹을
이끌다 수감되었죠
35 years ago,
he was in prison for leading
a Communist rebel group.
출소하고 나서는 마약 거래에 뛰어들었죠
When he got out,
he moved into the drug trade.
만약 올랜도에게 누명을 씌우는 걸 돕지
않으면 내 주위 사람을 모두 죽이겠다고 했어요
He told me if I didn't
help him frame Orlando,
he would kill
everyone I care about.
왜 그 때 저희에게 오지 않았나요?
Why didn't you come to us?
그 사람 밑에서 일하기 때문이군요
Because you were
working for him.
아뇨 / 무슨 약점을 잡고 있는 겁니까?
No.
What does he have on you?
돈을 받았어요. 콜롬비아에 유리한
미국 마약 정책을 지원해주는 대가로요
I took money.
For pushing a favorable
U.S. drug policy in Colombia.
딱 한 번이였죠. 그걸로 끝이었어요
Just once.
That was it.
하지만...
And then...
그걸로 당신을 부하삼았군요 / 그래요
And then he owned you.
Yeah.
그 자는 당신의 조국을 공격했습니다
압니다 / 이름을 알려주실 건가요?
He attacked your country.
Are you gonna tell me
his name or not?
공식 확인은 나오지 않았지만 미 해군이
오늘 새벽 드론 습격으로
NEWSCASTER: There's no official
confirmation, yet,
but we have reports
that the U.S. Navy launched
a drone strike,
early this morning,
콜롬비아 마약 거물 아르만드 루나의
건물을 공격했다고 합니다
against the compound of Armand
Luna, a Colombian drug lord.
루머에 따르면 루나가 1979년 메트로폴리탄 국제공항
폭탄 테러에 연류되었다는 DNA 증거가 있다고 합니다
It is rumored that DNA evidence
has linked Luna
to the 1979 bombing
of Metropolitan
International Airport.
저희에게도 말씀해주시지 않을 건가요?
You gonna remain
silent, too, sir?
잡았네
We got him.
어쩌면 바리스타와 만나던 때가 조금 겹쳤을지도 몰라
So maybe it was just a
teensy little overlap
with the barista bit.
- 대체 얼마나 겹쳤다는 거야?
- 옛날 일이라고 말해놓고서는
Exactly how much overlap
are we talking about here?
You said this was
ancient history.
그렇지. 하지만 너를 믿을 수 있을지는 알아야겠어
It is, but I need to know
whether or not I can trust you.
나를 못 믿겠다는 말은 하지도 마, 맥기
Don't ever say you
can't trust me, McGee.
국장님
Director.
국방부에 브리핑을 하러 가야 하지만
개인적으로 두 분께 직접 감사를 표하고 싶었습니다
I have a debriefing
at the Pentagon,
but I just wanted to thank
you both personally.
감사합니다, 사령관
Thank you, Commander.
부하들을 전선에 직접 보냈으니까요
많은 사람들이 잊어버린 걸 위해서요
You put your men
on the line for a thing.
A thing that a lot
of people forgot about.
여러분은 잊지 않으셨죠
You didn't.
저희 어머니, 자매들과 형도요
그들도 감사의 뜻을 전했습니다
Neither did my mother, my
sisters or my big brother.
They thank you, too.
국장님, 대통령님 연락이예요
25분 후에 기자회견 예정이랍니다
It's the president,
Director.
Press conference starts
in 25 minutes.
가 봐야 겠군요. 다른 가족들에게도
그들이 잊히지 않았음을 알려줄 때가 되겠네요
Got to go.
Time to let the other
families know
that they weren't
forgotten, either.
우-라
Oorah.
Hey, guys.
Hey.
What's up, man?
Hey!
What's up, Palmer?
(chuckles)
(all laughing
and chatting happily)
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man